Guide to the Sara M. Evans Papers, 1959-2005 RL.10161
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Sara M. Evans papers
1959-2005
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Evans, Sara M. (Sara Margaret), 1943-
RL.10161
26.7 Linear Feet 16,688 items
Sara M. Evans is a Regents Professor Emeritus in the history department at the University of Minnesota. She specializes in American social and women's history of the 20th century. Collection consists of subject files, course materials, research files, publication materials, lectures, correspondence, project documentation, student course work and student activist work accumulated by Evans during her career as first a student, then a professor and historian, of women's history. Topics include feminism, minority women, religion, violence, civil rights, labor activism at Duke University, lesbianism, motherhood, feminist theology, employment, socialist feminism, Christian feminism, National Organization for Women, Organization of American Historians, and student activism. Collection contains materials used in the preparation of her publications, including Personal Politics. There are also lectures, academic correspondence, and administrative materials from her tenure at the University of Minnesota. Audiocassette tapes from a series of interviews conducted by Evans in her research for Personal Politics, as well as a slide show from a feminist organization are also included. Originals of the audio cassette tapes are closed to use. Patrons must request use copies to access the content of this material. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research. However, original audiovisual materials are closed to patron use.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Sara M. Evans Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2008 and 2009, as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
Biographical Note
Sara Evans was born in South Carolina in 1943, and lived in Texas before receiving her bachelor's degree in history from Duke University in 1966. She earned a master's degree in political science from the University of Chicago, and graduated from the University of North Carolina with a doctorate in American history. She spent her academic career teaching and researching women's history at the University of Minnesota from 1976 until her retirement in 2008. Her books include Personal Politics: The Roots of Women's Liberation in the Civil Rights Movement and the New Left (1979, 1980); Free Spaces: The Sources of Democratic Change in America (1986); Born for Liberty: A History of American Women (1989); Wage Justice: Comparable Worth and the Paradox of Technocratic Reform (1989); Journeys That Opened Up the World: Women, Student Christian Movements (2003), and Tidal Wave: How Women Changed America at Century's End (2003).
Collection Overview
The material in this collection includes subject files, course materials, research files, lectures, conference materials, professional correspondence, publication materials, project documentation, student course work, student activist work, and academic administrative documents. It was accumulated by Evans during her career as first a student, then a professor and historian of women's history. Materials range in date from 1959 through 2005.
Topics in the Subject Files and Course Materials series include feminism, minority women, religion, violence, civil rights, lesbianism, motherhood, employment, and socialist feminism. There are course outlines and syllabi from women's history courses Evans taught at the University of Minnesota dating from the 1970s through the 1990s. There are also materials docmenting student activist work by Evans while at Duke University. It includes petitions, newsletters, and other printed material supporting the activities of the American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees of the AFL-CIO at Duke University. The Publications series contains materials accumulated by Evans during the research for and the publication of her books. These materials include research notes, publicity, reviews, and illustrations. Most significantly, it includes interview transcripts, chapter notes, and a name index of feminist leaders for Evans' book Personal Politics. The Audiocassettes series contains interviews Evans recorded during her research for Personal Politics. It also contains research interviews Evans conducted in the early 1980s, as well as interviews with Evans. The Lectures series contains notes and transcripts from lectures Evans gave outside the University of Minnesota. The Correspondence, Projects, Feminist Theology, and Miscellany series contains professional correspondence, documentation of grant-funded projects, feminist theology conference materials, and Evans' early course work, including her dissertation and notes from a history class at Duke taught by Anne Firor Scott. Also notable are documentation of the University of Chicago's Vietnam War draft policies, and papers outlining Students for a Democratic Society policies from 1962-1963. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
Originals of the audio cassette tapes are closed to use.
Slides (photographs); Civil rights -- United States; Feminism -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Feminism -- Religious aspects -- Christianity; Feminism -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- United States; Feminist theology; Lesbian feminism; Minorities -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Student movements -- United States -- History; Women -- Violence against; Women's history -- United States; Women's rights -- United States; Audiovisual materials; Audiocassettes; Evans, Sara M. (Sara Margaret), 1943-; Duke University -- Student life; Evans, Sara M. (Sara Margaret), 1943-; Evans, Sara M. (Sara Margaret), 1943- -- Personal Politics; Organization of American Historians; National Organization for Women; University of Minnesota; Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture; AFL-CIO
- Course Materials and Subject Files, 1959-2001; 27 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  The materials in this series consist mostly of subject and research files accumulated by Evans during her career as a professor and historian of women's history. Subjects include feminism, minority women, religion, violence, civil rights, lesbianism, motherhood, socialist feminism, and employment. Other items include course and curricular materials, printed materials and publications, conference information, and some correspondence. This series includes a slide show from a feminist organization.
  Arrangement note
  For the most part, Evans' original arrangement and folder titles have been retained.
  - Course syllabi, 1977-1978 (Box 1)
  - Comparable worth class, 1974-1984 (Box 1)
  - UNC-Chapel Hill syllabi, 1964-1979 (Box 1)
  - Bacon's Rebellion, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Indian cultural response, 1971 (Box 1)
  - City on a hill, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Race and culture, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Puritan discussion, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Comparative women's history class, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Oral history, 1973-1979 (Box 1)
  - Oral history, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Social history of American women, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
  - History courses, 1988-1993, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Theory and practice of women's history, 1977-1981 (Box 1)
  - Women, work and family, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Peasant women, undated (Box 1)
  - Urban/artisanal life, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Mill towns, undated (Box 1)
  - From country to city, undated (Box 1)
  - Middle class family life, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Working class family life, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Class and gender: ideology of women's work, undated (Box 1)
  - Education and women's professions, undated (Box 1)
  - Women in the post-industrial economy, undated (Box 1)
  - Pink collar work, undated (Box 1)
  - Housewife and workwife, undated (Box 1)
  - Recent trends, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Public policy course, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Feminist approaches to history, 1977-1979 (Box 1)
  - Female experience: childhood, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Marriage, motherhood and the single state, undated (Box 1)
  - Housewife, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Work, war and religion among Indian women, undated (Box 2)
  - History course, UNC-Chapel Hill, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Older woman's guide to independent living, 1975-1976 (Box 2)
  - Politico, 1977 (Box 2)
  - Education, 1977 (Box 2)
  - Search for autonomy, 1982 (Box 2)
  - Women in ancient history, 1977 (Box 2)
  - Middle ages and renaissance, 1979 (Box 2)
  - Shapes of women's lives, undated (Box 2)
  - Industrialization, undated (Box 2)
  - English women, undated (Box 2)
  - Social movements, undated (Box 2)
  - Women's history, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Feminism and methodology, undated (Box 2)
  - Survey syllabi, 1974-1976 (Box 2)
  - History syllabus, 1974 (Box 2)
  - American feminism seminar, 1974-1992 (Box 2)
  - Course ideas, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Seminar, 1979 (Box 2)
  - Women's studies, 1982 (Box 2)
  - Syllabi, 1985-1989 (Box 2)
  - World history, 1992 (Box 2)
  - Family sistory, 1978 (Box 2)
  - Women's studies, 1982 (Box 2)
  - Women's studies, 1983-1988 (Box 2)
  - Women in U.S. history, 1976-1978 (Box 2)
  - Cumulative file, 1976-1983 (Box 2)
  - Introduction, 1977-1983 (Box 2)
  - The Puritan family, 1983 (Box 2)
  - Women in American history, 1983 (Box 2)
  - Women in southern and middle colonies, 1988-1995 (Box 2)
  - Sexuality and gynecology, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Exceptional women, undated (Box 2)
  - Salem witch trials, undated (Box 2)
  - Enlightenment and revolution, undated (Box 2)
  - The Victorian lady, undated (Box 2)
  - Mill girls, new realities, undated (Box 2)
  - Utopian communities, undated (Box 2)
  - Black women and the slave family, undated (Box 2)
  - Race and sex, antebellum south, undated (Box 2)
  - Reform, abolition and women's rights, undated (Box 2)
  - Seneca Falls, undated (Box 2)
  - The female pioneer experience, undated (Box 3)
  - Cult of domesticity, undated (Box 3)
  - Women and the church, undated (Box 3)
  - Civil wars and reconstruction, undated (Box 3)
  - Women in modern America, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Women's studies senior seminar, 1976-1977 (Box 3)
  - Women in modern America, 1995 (Box 3)
  - Course syllabi, 1986-1989, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Course materials, 1979-1985 (Box 3)
  - Printed materials
    - Readings and resources on Asian-American Women, 1990 (Box 3)
    - Readings and Resources on American Indian Women, 1989 (Box 3)
  - Native American Women Bibliography, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Multicultural Women's Sourcebook, 1982 (Box 4)
  - To All Inquiring Friends: Letters, Diaries, and Essays in North Dakota, 1979 (Box 4)
  - Women's History Resources, 1989 (Box 4)
  - Women, Cultural Diversity and the Curriculum, undated (Box 4)
  - Teaching Women's History, 1977 (Box 4)
  - Women in U.S. History, 1976 (Box 4)
  - Subject Files
    - Sexuality, 1996 (Box 4)
    - Reproductive rights, 1986-1997 (Box 4)
    - Motherhood and birthright, 1971-1989 (Box 4)
    - Portrayals of women in popular culture, 1990-1997 (Box 4)
    - Sports, 1974-1998 (Box 4)
    - Misc. subjects, 1970-1998 (Box 4)
  - Feminism in the 1990s, 1987-2001, 3 folders (Box 5)
  - The next generation, 1989-2001 (Box 5)
  - International organizing, 1994-1999 (Box 5)
  - Backlash and anti-feminism, 1990 (Box 5)
  - Women's health, 1971-1975 (Box 5)
  - Men's movement, 1993 (Box 5)
  - Sources, 1977-1995 (Box 6)
  - Pornography, 1970-1994 (Box 6)
  - Discrimination, 1970 (Box 6)
  - The woman question, 1970-1976 (Box 6)
  - Employment issues, 1972-2000 (Box 6)
  - Violence and women, 1973-1994 (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous, 1992-1994 (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous, 1984-1992 (Box 7)
  - Iowa conference, 1977 (Box 7)
  - Center for Advanced Feminist Studies, 1987-1991 (Box 7)
  - Comparative women's history, 1991-1996 (Box 7)
  - Department of Labor, 1959-1967 (Box 7)
  - Printed Materials
    - Voice of the Women's Liberation Movement, 1968-1969 (Box 7)
    - Radical Historian's Newsletter, 1989 (Box 7)
    - Pamphlets, 1922-1980 (Box 7)
  - Curricular materials, undated, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - National teleconference for women in eigher education, 1995-1999 (Box 8)
  - Bibliographies, 1990 (Box 8)
  - Printed curricular materials, undated (Box 8)
  - Annual reports, 1990-1995 (Box 9)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1989 (Box 9)
  - Activities, 1986 (Box 9)
  - Unpublished papers, 1982 and undated (Box 9)
  - Women's history, 1975 (Box 9)
  - Southern sit-in movement, 1960 (Box 9)
  - Photocopied letters to Betty Friedan, 1964 (Box 9)
  - Feminist scholars update, 1988 (Box 9)
  - Women in American society, 1973 (Box 9)
  - Women, the longest revolution, 1966 (Box 9)
  - Placing women in the past, 1997 (Box 9)
  - Whole women catalog, 1974 (Box 9)
  - Southern student organizing committee, 1965 (Box 9)
  - New York Times Book Review, 1979-1986 (Box 9)
  - Book reviews, 1989-2001 (Box 9)
  - Evaluations, 1988 (Box 9)
  - Anniversary celebration, 1990 (Box 9)
  - Barnard conference, 1991 (Box 9)
  - Sources and notes, 1998 (Box 9)
  - Women's art, 1973-1997 (Box 10)
  - Women's music, 1974-1990 (Box 10)
  - Women's culture, 1971-1996 (Box 10)
  - Lesbian music, 1973-1994 (Box 10)
  - Lesbian art, 1974-1997 (Box 10)
  - Mainstream lesbians, 1979-1993 (Box 10)
  - Lesbian writing, 1971-1985 (Box 10)
  - Lesbian political activism, 1973-1999 (Box 10)
  - Lesbian feminism, 1973-1977 (Box 10)
  - Lesbian feminism debates, 1972-1984 (Box 10)
  - Lesbian racism, 1973-1990 (Box 10)
  - Issues and trends in the lesbian community, 1972-1999 (Box 10)
  - Socialist feminism, 1972-1989, 4 folders (Box 11)
  - Evans' comments on unpublished manuscript, 1997 (Box 11)
  - Socialism and feminism, 1970-1977 (Box 12)
  - Student activism, 1974-1977 (Box 12)
  - Slideshow: Time is Passing: A Common Women's History, by the Circle of the Witch Theaters, Minneapolis, Minn. (Box 12)
  - Upper Midwest Women's History Center, 1996 (Box 12)
  - Feminism, popular views, 1972-1992 (Box 12)
  - Coops, communes and collectives, 1974-1994 (Box 12)
  - Battered women's shelters, 1975-1987 (Box 12)
  - Women's centers, 1972-1974 (Box 12)
  - Feminist businesses, 1973-1979 (Box 12)
  - Institutions, 1973-1980 (Box 12)
  - Into the mainstream, 1979-1998 (Box 12)
  - Betty Friedan, 1995-1999 (Box 13)
  - Gloria Steinem, 1973-1995 (Box 13)
  - Organizations, 1970-1972 (Box 13)
  - Contemporary views of feminism, 1970-1980 (Box 13)
  - Women's movement, 1973-1974 (Box 13)
  - Sources, 1993-1998 (Box 13)
  - General context, 1990s (Box 13)
  - Multiculturalism and political correctness, 1990-1998 (Box 13)
  - Women's issues, 1990-1998, 1 of 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Women's issues, 1990-1998, 2 of 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Women and work, 1994-2000 (Box 14)
  - Motherhood, family and work, 1993-2000 (Box 14)
  - Women and politics, 1992-1999 (Box 14)
  - Anita Hill, 1992-1997 (Box 14)
  - Sexual harassment, 1986-1999 (Box 15)
  - Research, 1979-1999 (Box 15)
  - Retrospectives, 1993-1997 (Box 15)
  - Continuing education for women, 1969-1975 (Box 15)
  - Women's studies, 1970s, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Women's studies, 1980s (Box 15)
  - Women's studies, 1990s, 3 folders (Box 15)
  - Feminist scholarship, 1971-1999 (Box 16)
  - Gay and lesbian studies and faculty, 1992-1998 (Box 16)
  - Notes and bibliographies, 1998 (Box 16)
  - Organizing women, 1979 (Box 16)
  - National women's agenda, 1976 (Box 16)
  - Equal Rights Amendment (ERA), 1970-1976 (Box 16)
  - Electoral politics, 1983-1994 (Box 16)
  - Title IX, 1981 (Box 16)
  - Women's Equity Resource Center (WEEA), 1981-1992 (Box 16)
  - WEEA, 1982-1994 (Box 16)
  - Coalition on women and the budget, 1983-1984 (Box 16)
  - National Organization for Women (NOW), 1971-1995 (Box 16)
  - League of Women Voters, 1970-1988 (Box 16)
  - National Women's Politics Caucus (NWPC), 1973-1987 (Box 17)
  - Institute for Women's Policy Research (IWPR), 1997-1998 (Box 17)
  - Unions, 1974-1998, 3 folders (Box 17)
  - Girls' organizations, 1974-1994 (Box 17)
  - Bibliographies and sources, 1985 (Box 17)
  - Women and religion, 1975-1995 (Box 17)
  - Women and religion, 1970-1988, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Women in denominations, 1976-1998 (Box 18)
  - Women challenge the church, 1971-1992, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Re-Imagining Conference, (feminist theology) 1993-1998, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Gays, lesbians and the church, 1996-1999 (Box 19)
  - Alternative religion, 1985-2000 (Box 19)
  - Women of color, 1971-1999, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Overviews of primary sources, 1974-2000 (Box 19)
  - Black women, 1960s-1990s, 4 folders (Box 19)
  - Black women politicians, 1970-1971 (Box 19)
  - Individual women, 1997-1998 (Box 19)
  - Race and the women's movement, 1970s-1980s (Box 19)
  - Latinas, 1977-1997 (Box 20)
  - Native American women, 1968-1998 (Box 20)
  - Asian-American women, 1971-1989 (Box 20)
  - Ms. magazine, 1973-1975 (Box 20)
  - Secondary sources, 1970-1999 (Box 20)
  - Consciousness raising, 1971-1998 (Box 20)
  - Marlene Dixon sit-in, 1969, folder 1 of 2 (Box 20)
  - Marlene Dixon sit-In, 1969, folder 2 of 2 (Box 21)
  - Women's liberation, 1960s-1970s, 2 folders (Box 21)
  - Newsletters, 1968-1975 (Box 21)
  - Meetings and conferences, 1960s-1970s (Box 21)
  - Chicago Women's Liberation Union (CWLU), 1975-1998 (Box 21)
  - The Furies, 1972-1988 (Box 22)
  - Dayton women's liberation, 1975-1997 (Box 22)
  - Redstockings, 1991-1998 (Box 22)
  - Lollipop Power, 1970-1971 (Box 22)
  - Actions, 1970 (Box 22)
  - Gay-straight split, 1970-1977 (Box 22)
  - Eclipse, 1971-1983 (Box 22)
  - Gilman minutes, 1975 (Box 22)
  - Radical women's movement, 1968 (Box 22)
  - Chicago Women's Liberation Conference, 1968 (Box 22)
  - Female studies bibliography, 1970 (Box 23)
  - Conference Group on Women in the Historical Profession (CGWH) Newsletter, 1977-1983 (Box 23)
  - Book reviews, 1975-1992 (Box 23)
  - Early work, 1973-1974 (Box 23)
  - Feminism and historical consciousness, 1982 (Box 23)
  - Job talk, 1975 (Box 23)
  - Family and children's service, 1976-1978 (Box 23)
  - Lectures, 1980-1991 (Box 23)
  - University governance, 1998-1999 (Box 23)
  - Association of Governing Boards of Universities and Colleges (AGB) statement, 1998 (Box 23)
  - Grant application, 1980 (Box 23)
  - Lectures, 1974-1990 (Box 24)
  - Grants, 1980-1981 (Box 24)
  - Lectures, 1980-1993, 3 folders (Box 24)
  - Articles, undated (Box 24)
  - Conference on Women's Movement in U.S. and Canada, 1989 (Box 25)
  - Maiden Rock Seminar, 1977 (Box 25)
  - History of African Peoples Seminar, 1977 (Box 25)
  - Forum on Feminism keynote address, 1988 (Box 25)
  - Seneca Falls Conference, 1983 (Box 25)
  - Berkshire Conference, 1974 (Box 25)
  - Nairobi Conference, 1985 (Box 25)
  - Berkshire Conference, 1978-1993, 5 folders (Box 25)
  - Fergus Falls Conference, 1995 (Box 25)
  - Wingspread Conference, 1981 (Box 25)
  - Marable paper, 1983 (Box 25)
  - Midwest academy, undated (Box 25)
  - Chapel Hill Seminar, 1984 (Box 26)
  - Continuing education, 1978 (Box 26)
  - Ramsey Jr. High School, 1986 (Box 26)
  - Hamilton College, 1990 (Box 26)
  - Park Service, 1981 (Box 26)
  - Berkshire critique, 1981 (Box 26)
  - Illegitimacy project, 1982 (Box 26)
  - Star Tribune Op-Ed, 1997 (Box 26)
  - Teach-in, 1991 (Box 26)
  - Lecture notes, 1984 (Box 26)
  - Panel comments, 1988 (Box 26)
  - Freshman comp., 1990 (Box 26)
  - Lecture, 1998 (Box 26)
  - Duke Civil Rights Conference, 1977 (Box 26)
  - Leadership Conference, 1991 (Box 26)
  - Virginia Civil Rights Conference, 1988-1989 (Box 26)
  - Hispanic Feminist Conference, 1988 (Box 26)
  - OAH, 1988-1995 (Box 26)
  - YMCA Conference, 1987 (Box 26)
  - ERA statement, 1981 (Box 26)
  - Wingspread Conference, 1988 (Box 26)
  - Sarah Lawrence Seminar, 1976 (Box 26)
  - VCU Seminar, 1990 (Box 26)
  - Spring Hill Conference, 1979 (Box 26)
  - Duke reunion, 1986 (Box 26)
  - Summer institute, 1980 (Box 26)
  - Unionizing materials, Duke University, 1966 (Box 27)
- Publications Series, 1964-1998; 11 boxes
  Contains notes, interview transcripts, reviews, research, correspondence and other materials relating to Evans' publications, including Personal Politics, Born for Liberty, and Wage Justice.
  - Personal Politics (Box 28A)
    - Interview notes, 1972-1974 (Box 28A)
    - Correspondence, 1974-1990 (Box 28A)
    - Documents, 1965-1978 (Box 28A)
    - Notes for conclusion, 1974-1975 (Box 28A)
    - Notes and transcripts, 1964 (Box 28A)
    - Notes, 1973-1984 (Box 28A)
    - Interview transcripts, 1972-1987, 2 folders (Box 28A)
    - Interview notes, 1982-1997 (Box 28B)
    - Interviews and notes, 1979 (Box 28B)
  - Personal Politics (Box 29)
    - Interview transcripts, 1973, 2 folders (Box 29)
    - Notes, chapters 1-4, undated, 4 folders (Box 29)
    - Notes, chapter 5 (Box 29A)
    - Notes, 1965-1975 (Box 29A)
    - Comments, 1975 (Box 29A)
  - Personal Politics (Box 30)
    - Interview transcripts, 1972-1977 (Box 30)
    - Interview transcripts and notes, 1973 and undated (Box 30)
    - Research files, 1968-1969, 2 folders (Box 30)
    - Reviews, 1979 (Box 30)
  - Research notes, 1974 and undated (Box 34)
  - Notes for women's liberation, 1973 and undated (Box 34)
  - Women's liberation research files, 1967-1994, 2 folders (Box 34)
  - National Congress of Neighborhood Women, 1976-1983, 3 folders (Box 34)
  - Working class women's movement, 1982-1983 (Box 34)
  - Women and work, 1981-1983, 2 folders (Box 35)
  - Women employed, 1981-1982 (Box 35)
  - Correspondence, 1988-2001 (Box 35)
  - Miranda Foundation, 1988 (Box 35)
  - Interview notes, 1977-1998, 3 folders (Box 35)
  - Joyce Miller, 1974 (Box 36)
  - Completed survey forms, 1969, 3 folders (Box 36)
  - Articles on women's surnames, 1973-1990, 2 folders (Box 37)
  - Wage Justice reviews, 1988-1990 (Box 37)
  - Comparable worth correspondence, 1985-1987 (Box 37)
  - Wage Justice promotional materials, 1989-1990 (Box 37)
  - Comparable worth project reports, 1984-1986 (Box 37)
  - Comparable worth conference, 1985 (Box 37)
  - National Academy of Sciences grant (Box 37)
  - Comparable worth articles, 1986-1988 (Box 37)
  - Comparable worth interview notes, 1986-1988 (Box 37)
  - Born for Liberty, 1987-1991, 2 folders (Box 38)
  - Book reviews, Born for Liberty and Wage Justice, 1989-1991 (Box 38)
  - Born for Liberty photo inserts, 1989 and undated (Box 38)
  - Born for Liberty photo permissions, 1989-1990, 2 folders (Box 38)
- Audiocassettes Series, 1972-1989; 1; 256 items
  - Jimmy Weinstein and Anne Farrar, DeKalb, Illinois, 1973 July 5; 1
    Scope and Contents
    Contains taped interviews Evans recorded during her research for Personal Politics in the 1970s. It also contains a group of interviews Evans conducted in the early 1980s for her books Free Spaces and Wage Justice. At the end are a group of miscellaneous interviews and discussions, including several interviews with Evans.
    - Cassette original (Box 31, Audio-cassette RL10161-CS-0001)
    - Compact disc use copy (Box 47, Audio-disc RL10161-CD-0090)
    - Compact disc use copy (Box 47, Audio-disc RL10161-CD-0091)
  - Steve Max and Heather Booth, Chicago, 1973 July 9; 2
    - Cassette original (Box 31, Audio-cassette RL10161-CS-0002)
    - Compact disc use copy (Box 47, Audio-disc RL10161-CD-0091)
    - Compact disc use copy (Box 47, Audio-disc RL10161-CD-0092)
  - Heather Booth, Vivian Rothstein, 1973 July 10; 3
    - Cassette original (Box 31, Audio-cassette RL10161-CS-0003)